# **Jonathan Vargas**

San Antonio, TX (210) 550 - 6119 11jonathanvargas11@gmail.com

#### Analyst, Developer, Penetration Tester.

I am a Senior undergraduate at the University of Texas at San Antonio majoring in Cyber Security and Information Systems. I am enthusiastic about hardening operating systems and network security and strive to lead the next generation of cyber security professionals. My goal is to find opportunities to apply my diligently-learned principles of security with a team that encourages innovation and leadership.

I have authored various penetration testing methodology articles on my website, organized a cyber security CTF competition for two ethical hacking online communities, and acquired industry IT experience during my undergraduate studies through two internships and one contract opportunity. Through extracurricular activities, I have consulted with leaders in my field on security practices and headed an on-campus organization with weekly lessons.

My motivation to develop secure networks has led to obtaining the CompTIA Security+ and Offensive Security Certified Professional (OSCP) certifications.

#### Certifications / Licenses

#### Offensive Security Certified Professional

01/2021

The OSCP exam is a 24-hour practical ethical hacking test offered by Offensive Security. By becoming an Offensive Security Certified Professional, I have demonstrated the ability to use persistence, creativity, and perceptiveness to identify vulnerabilities in remote Windows and Linux servers while executing organized attacks under tight time constraints.

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/bbe5bdbb-3a9d-4cea-972c-6aee0974e8d6/public url

## CompTIA Security+

08/2020

By obtaining this certification, I have demonstrated the skills necessary to perform core security functions required of any cybersecurity role. I understand how to identify and address potential threats, attacks and vulnerabilities and I have established techniques in risk management, risk mitigation, threat management and intrusion detection.

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/75da2bbe-0014-4f4d-9f9d-281c19150a0f/public url

## **Work Experience**

# **Cyber Security CTF Organizer**

08/2020 to 08/2020

Self

San Antonio, TX

- Executed an open capture-the-flag competition for members of the Try Hack Me and Hack The Box ethical
  hacking communities. Two teams of five members were tasked with exploiting a remote server, gaining access,
  then establishing tighter security controls in order for the opposing team to fail at breaching entry.
- Assembled a collection of three exploitable machines containing vulnerabilities in line with the Open Web Application Security Project's (OWASP) top ten security risks.
- Researched real-world security compromising incidents and integrated recent exploits into the competition's vulnerable machines.

# **SQL** Developer

02/2020 to 08/2020

Ward North American

San Antonio, TX

- · Optimize MS SQL reporting scripts for lower data retrieval latency.
- Debug live SQL reports for misreported values.
- Collaborate with various department managers to build new tables and reports that fit the department's requirements.
- Write over 5,000 lines of code monthly to adjust for the company's changing data management practices.

#### **President**

05/2019 to 05/2020

**UTSA Swing Dance Society** 

San Antonio, TX

- Headed a student-led organization to preserve the social dance and culture of the swing jazz era
- · Orchestrated weekly dance instruction
- · Cultivated a Board of Executives
- · Partnered with community and intercollegiate organizations

#### **IT Intern**

03/2019 to 02/2020

Ward North American

San Antonio, TX

- Spearheaded the development of aggregation software to understand sales trends
- Developed two complex SQL and JDBC algorithms to fully automate corporate budget analysis
- Inspired the prototyping of Ward University: a learning management system for small corporations.
- Collaborated closely with cloud service provider to ensure network reliability.
- Offered expert IT troubleshooting and consultation for software and hardware solutions.
- · Gained experience using Wireshark to monitor network activity and identify network issues.
- Developed automated emails to be sent out to customers and agents.

# **Cyber Security Intern**

07/2017 to 03/2018

Alamo City Engineering Services

San Antonio, TX

- · Acquired industry hands-on open source intelligence experience through utilizing deep web data crawling APIs.
- Collaborated with a team to delegate tasks and develop strategies to implement information system automation software.

#### **Education**

# **University of Texas at San Antonio**

Bachelor's Cyber Security, Information Systems San Antonio, TX 08/2017 to 05/2021

# **Groups**

# **UTSA Computer Security Association**

- Attended weekly discussions on current security trends, automation tools, and information security principles.
- Visited online workshops for further developing cyber security skills such as risk mitigation, executing security assessments for real world companies, and security hardening tools.
- Consulted with higher-experienced members of my field to explore industry standards and practices.

# **UTSA Swing Dance Society**

- Headed a student-led organization to preserve the social dance and culture of the swing jazz era
- · Orchestrated weekly dance instruction
- · Cultivated a Board of Executives
- · Partnered with community organizations.

#### Links

https://vargasportfolio.github.io/ ~ Cyber Security Portfolio and Penetration Test Writeups